

Senior Software Engineer seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, Technical Lead. Strong in design and problem-solving. Strong in C#.Net core, Microservices, Rest API, MVC, Entity Framework, Azure, Asp.net Core, Jquery



Current Designation: Technical Lead Total Experience: 9 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Mindtree Notice Period: Currently Serving Notice Period

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: MCA [Computers]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: C#.Net core, Microservices, Rest API, MVC, Entity Framework, Azure, Asp.net Core, Jquery, JSON,

Javascript, HTML, SQL, Oracle

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: Jan-Mar 2021 Last Modified: Jan-Mar 2021

# **Summary**

With 9 years of experience in the IT industry in various technologies. A domain-driven, customer-focused, articulate and analytical Consultant. Strong in design and integration of Problem-solving skills. Expert in C#.NET, Microservices, Web API Core, .Net Core, MVC, WCF, Entity Framework, jQuery, Java script and T-SQL with database analysis and design, Microsoft Azure Services. Skilled in developing business plans, requirements specifications, user Documentation and architectural systems research. Interested in a challenging technical track career in an application and product development environment.

# **Work Experience**

**Mindtree** as Technical Lead Sep 2020 to Till Date

With 9 years of experience in the IT industry in various technologies. A domain-driven, customer-focused, articulate and analytical Consultant. Strong in design and integration of problem-solving skills. Expert in C#.NET, Microservices, Web API Core, .Net Core, MVC, WCF, Entity Framework, jQuery, Javascript, and T-SQL with database analysis and design, Microsoft Azure Services. Skilled in developing business plans, requirements specifications, user Documentation, and architectural systems research. Interested in a challenging technical track career in an application and product development environment.

#### **Dell Technologies** as Principle Software Engineer Nov 2015 to Jun 2020

Roles and Responsibilities: -

- \* Backend developer. Developing Microservices, APIs on .Net Core
- \* Fixing major production issues and deploying to productions
- Handling the compliance tasks
- Involved in product load testing
- \* Developing the utility tools to fix the failed orders
- \* Good hands-on Monitoring tools like Splunk, riverbed, Kibana
- Visit US to support black Friday sales
- \* Modernization of the legacy code and move to PCF and Azure with microservices.

#### **UST Global** as Software Engineer

Oct 2014 to Nov 2015

client location Dell and then converted to permanent employee in Dell.

#### ISS SOFTTECH Pvt Ltd as Software Engineer

Jun 2013 to Sep 2014

client location HP

Advaita Software as Software Engineer

Jan 2012 to May 2013

Mac Technology Services Pvt Ltd as Software Engineer

Feb 2011 to Dec 2011

### **Education**

UG: BCA (Computers) from DAAS College, Dehradun, affiliated to M.C.R.P. University, Bhopal in 2010

PG: MCA (Computers), Correspondence/Distance Learning from Sikkim Manipal University (SMU) in 2014

### **IT Skills**

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience	
.Net Core	5.0	2021	3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
MicroServices	5.0	2021	3 Year(s)	
REST API	5.0	2021	6 Year(s)	
Microsoft Azure		2021	3 Year(s)	
C#	8	2021	9 Year(s)	
ASP.NET	3.1	2021	9 Year(s)	
MVC Core	3.1	2021	8 Year(s)	
SQL SERVER, LINQ, ORACLE, Cosmo	2019	2020	9 Year(s)	
.NET	8	2021	9 Year(s)	
JQUERY		2021	9 Year(s)	
JavaScript		2021	9 Year(s)	

# Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Kannada				

## **Affirmative Action**

## **Work Authorization**

1/22/2021 https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=e91b112169024c6cf1ad4b9fda9e4ba65a58080742130f440144105b0e...

Category: General Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No Employment Status: Full time